Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Catherine and today
we're going on a little driving lesson.
That's right, we're
going to learn how to
drive, but not only
how to drive, but all the
vocabulary and words
associated to this activity.
So why don't we listen to this dialogue for
the first time and we'll be back to explain
it.
Okay, I'm ready for my driving
lesson, should I start the car?
Hold on there, Fiddy Polybee, first
let's go over things one more time.
Now before you even
think of starting the
car, make sure your
seat is at a comfortable
position and you can grip
the steering wheel firmly.
Next, check your rear view mirrors
to make sure you can see properly.
We've been through this a million
times, let's get going already, I'm ready!
Fine, start the car.
Okay, now gently step on
the clutch and shift to first gear.
Good, now accelerate gently,
let go of the clutch as you do it.
There we go, good.
I'm doing it, I'm driving, this is
awesome, let's turn some music on.
See if your eyes on the
road, no music, we are
coming up to a red
light, step on the brakes.
What are you doing?
I said the brakes, look
out for those people,
get off the sidewalk,
get out of my way,
this is just like playing
video games, it's the
police, pull over, they'll
never take me alive.
Alright, great, so it's a great driving
lesson just like the video games.
Well, hopefully not like
video games, we don't
want to hurt anyone, but
that comes a little bit later.
First, let's check out
some of these very
important phrases in
today's language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright, so on language
takeaway we have five
words for you today, starting
with the first one, the steering wheel.
Okay, steering wheel,
so this comes from
the fact that we have
a wheel that we use to
turn the car left and
right, and so that's called
to steer, to change the
direction of something.
So the verb to steer
is to take it left to right.
Exactly, so steering
wheel is the instrument
that we use to change
the car's direction.
Very good, and well
apart from this instrument,
also in order to look
to other cars that
are behind you, you would
look at your rear view mirror.
Great, so rear view
mirror, this is a mirror
that you have in front
of you in the middle
of the car, and you look at this mirror
to find out if there are cars behind you.
So it's a rear view, that
means you're looking
at the back, rear
means back or behind.
What about the mirrors that are
on the side of the car, on the doors?
Those are called side view mirrors.
Side view mirrors.
Okay, very good.
And while moving on,
he was instructing her on
how to drive, and he
said step on the clutch.
Well, this is an important word for
those of you who are driving manual cars.
That means that you
have to control the way
that the gas goes into
the engine by yourself.
And so a clutch is a
pedal, it's the third pedal on
the left, and you push
this pedal to change gears.
Okay, so some cars they don't have this.
For those of you who
don't don't worry about
it, but if you do, a clutch is on
the far left, it's the third pedal.
Okay, so this is for a manual car, manual
transmission car, because many people have
automatics where you just accelerate
and the car automatically changes gears.
Exactly.
And so a lot of Europeans drive
manual cars and have this clutch.
Okay.
So you step on the
clutch, and in order to
change gear, you say
to shift into first gear.
That's right, because
if you're driving, you
know that you can't go
from first to fifth gear.
There's four or five gears, and so you
have to go one, two, three, four, five.
You have to go in order.
So we're shifting.
We're moving up, or we're moving down.
So that's called to shift.
All right, to shift.
And now in the dialer, we
heard to shift into first gear.
So that's what it's called.
Exactly.
And so normally the
car starts in and neutral.
That was when you're at
a break, you're at a stop.
And if you want to
start the car, you have to
shift to first gear,
and that's the lowest.
That's going to help the car go.
Okay.
So to shift into first
gear, awesome vocabulary.
I think this is really useful,
especially because it's very specific.
So you don't really see it very often in
anywhere, but sometimes you need to use it.
That's right.
And it's especially useful if you're
trying to teach someone how to drive.
Yeah, because not everyone
knows how to drive manual.
Exactly.
Listen to the dialogue again, and
we'll be back to explain fluency builder.
Okay, I'm ready for my driving lesson.
Should I start the car?
Hold on there, Fiddy Polybee.
First let's go over things one more time.
Now before you even
think of starting the
car, make sure your
seat is at a comfortable
position, and you can grip
the steering wheel firmly.
Next, check your rear view mirrors
to make sure you can see properly.
We've been through this a million times.
Let's get going already.
I'm ready.
Fine.
Start the car.
Okay, now gently step on
the clutch and shift to first gear.
Good.
Now accelerate gently and
let go of the clutch as you do it.
There we go.
Good.
I'm doing it.
I'm driving.
This is awesome.
Let's hand some music on.
Keep your eyes on the road.
No music.
We are coming up to a red light.
Step on the brakes.
What are you doing?
I said the brakes.
Look out for those people.
Get off the sidewalk.
Get out of my way.
Oh, this is just like playing video games.
It's the police.
Pull over.
They'll never take me alive.
All right, we're back.
So now why don't we take a look
at four key phrases in fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Well the first phrase is maybe
the most important when driving.
It's the first thing you do.
You start the car.
All right, so you don't say
you turn on the car right now.
So you put the key in the
ignition and you start the car.
That means you you turn it on.
What about to when you want
to turn off the car, turn the car off.
You say stop the engine.
Stop the car.
Stop the engine.
Right.
All right, very good.
Moving on.
Our next phrase is a million times.
Why is this a phrase a million times?
This is pretty literal, right?
We've been through this a million times.
Well, no, it's not
literal otherwise I think
you're my kill the
person because a million
times mean means that we've had this
same conversation many, many, many times.
But you can't actually
have it a million times.
That's that's way too many.
So it's an exaggeration.
Yeah, it's a way to say a lot so I've
heard him say this a million times.
I've heard this story a
million times or I've done this.
I've turned the car on a million times.
Okay.
Awesome.
Now, well, they were
driving and they heard a
police siren and the
guy told her to pull over.
Okay.
So this is a very
common car phrase again,
especially when you're
dealing with the police.
So to pull over means to slow the car down
and to stop it on the side of the road.
So you could hear a
policeman say pull over.
So pull over your car.
That means slow down
and stop the car on the
side because obviously you can't
stop in the middle of the road.
Right.
So your mobile phone will ring as
well and you don't have a hands free.
So you have to pull over to the side so
you can pick up the phone usually, right?
Exactly.
Or you could say, "Hey,
mom, could you pull over?
I have to use the restroom.
" Exactly.
Awesome.
All right.
And our last phrase for today is to
take me alive, to take someone alive.
They'll never take me alive.
All right.
So the character says,
and so this is a phrase
that we use when we're talking about
people who are running away from the law.
So there he says, "They will never
capture me and if they do, I'll be dead.
" So he's saying,
"Either I run free or I die.
" All right.
So to take someone alive is basically that.
But is it literal?
Would you say,
"No, this is not literal.
" He's saying, "They'll
never catch me.
" Okay.
Very good.
All right.
So that's all the phrases
we have for today.
Why don't we listen to this dialogue
for the last time and we'll be back.
Okay, I'm ready for my driving lesson.
Should I start the car?
Hold on there, Fitty-Pawdie.
First let's go over things one more time.
Now before you even
think of starting the
car, make sure your
seat is at a comfortable
position and you can grip
the steering wheel firmly.
Next, check your rear view mirrors
to make sure you can see properly.
We've been through this a million times.
Let's get going already.
I'm ready.
Fine.
What's the car?
Okay.
Now gently step on the
clutch and shift to first gear.
Good.
Now accelerate gently, let
go of the clutch as you do it.
There we go.
Good.
I'm doing it.
I'm driving.
This is awesome.
Let's turn some music on.
Keep your eyes on the road.
No music.
We are coming up to a red light.
Step on the brakes.
What are you doing?
I said the brakes.
Look out for those people.
Get off the sidewalk.
Get out of my way.
This is just like playing video games.
It's the police.
Pull over.
It'll never take me alive.
All right, we're back so driving now.
This is interesting because
as you mentioned, a
lot of people in America usually
have automatic transmissions.
Whereas in Europe, maybe
they have manual transmissions.
Is there a reason for that, do you think?
I'm not sure what the reason would be.
I think a lot of American car makers
manufacture more automatic cars in general.
Some people say that it's because people
in America are less concerned with gas.
But if you have a manual transmission, you
can actually conserve a bit of gas and so
because gas prices
in Europe are higher,
generally, when people are interested
in having manual transmissions.
Also, I remember when
I was younger, my dad
always bought cars that
had a manual transmission
because he said that if
ever they break down,
it's much easier and
cheaper to fix a car
that has a manual transmission
than it is to fix an automatic one.
That's right.
Well, I personally
think that it's better to
learn how to drive on
a manual transmission
car because you can
drive any car afterwards.
If you learn on an automatic, you'll
never know how to drive a manual.
There was also a case
on television recently
about a small child
that actually the dialogue
is based on it is he
took his dad's car and
he was like seven years
old and he was driving
and was being chased by the
police and then he pulled into
his house and got out of
the car and ran into the house.
So obviously he was an underage driver but
he didn't get into much trouble but it was
interesting because
he drove very, very well.
And basically almost
learned it by game
simulators, by video games on
how you drive on a video game.
Oh, wow.
Yes.
So if you have any
questions, any comments
or any other suggestions for lessons,
please come to our website, englishpod.com.
And we'll see you guys there.
Bye, everyone.